嘿，大家好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列
hey, what's up guys my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series
那么上次我们讲了预编译头文件，如果你们还没看的话，一定要去看那个视频
so last time we took a look at precompiled headers, definitely check out that video, if you haven't already
今天我们将最终创建一个窗口，这样就可以在窗口上随意添加东西
and today we're gonna be finally creating a window, so that we can random stuff onto our window
所以我一直在思考，什么时候在整个游戏引擎系列中这么做
so I was really contemplating, when to do this in this whole game engine series
因为我的意思是，从技术上讲，在我考虑添加一个窗口之前，我可能已经做了很多事情
because I mean, technically speaking, I probably would have done a lot of stuff before I even considered adding a window
如果我只是以一名自我工程师的身份在自己的时间内制作游戏引擎
if I was just making a game engine in my own time as kind of a self engineer
我会确保在我做窗口之前我已经做了很多东西
I would make sure that I had a lot of stuff already done before I kind of just made the window
制作窗口和做所有这些图形的东西是很多人做的第一步
making the window and kind of doing all of that graphic stuff is what a lot of people do as their first kind of steps
当你们学到更多，当你们更熟悉游戏引擎的类型
as you kind of learn more though, and as you get more familiar with what kind of a game engine
游戏引擎实际上是怎样的架构，它看起来是什么样的，很明显，它不仅仅是一个窗口
how a game engine is actually architectures, and what that looks like, it becomes apparent that, there's so much more than a window
同时添加一个窗口是有用的，因为你们可以，像渲染文本和显示调试信息
and whilst adding a window is useful, because you can, like render text and display debug information
可视化在你们的游戏引擎中运行的东西
and visualize things actually working in your game engine
事实上，你们知道的，游戏通常会渲染图像，那很重要
as well as the fact that you know, games typically render graphics, and that's kind of important
一旦你们把那个放在一边，游戏引擎实际上还有很多东西
once you kind of, if you put that aside, there's actually a lot of stuff to a game engine
比如事件系统，比如应用系统，比如层栈系统，比如输入管理器
like the event system, like the application system, like a layer stack system, like I don't know, input managers
所有这些实际上已经，实际上必须要做的事情，可能在你们有一个窗口之前很久
all of that stuff that actually have, that actually has to be done, potentially long before you have a window
所以我决定现在就创建一个窗口
so I've kind of made this decision to actually make a window now though
因为我觉得很多人可能开始失去兴趣了，而我不得不
because I feel like a lot of people are beginning to maybe lose a bit of interest, and I have to kind of
在整个游戏引擎系列中，我必须记住我不只是一个制作游戏引擎的软件工程师
in this whole game engine series, I have to actually remember that I'm not just a software engineer building a game engine
实际上我也在尝试教学，也在尝试一些娱乐，这样人们就会真正喜欢这些视频
I'm actually also trying to teach, and also trying to be somewhat entertaining, so that people are actually enjoying these videos
所以正因为如此，我做出了一些妥协，我们在同伴闲聊中谈了很多这个问题
and so because of that, there are kind of compromises that I make, and we talked a lot about this during the partner hang out
顺便说一下，如果你们还不知道，可以在patreon.com/thecherno上支持我
by the way, if you guys aren't aware, you can support me on p patreon.com/thecherno
如果达到了一定的等级，你们就会被邀请参加我们每月一次的伙伴聚会
and if you pledge a certain tier, you actually get invited to a partner hangout that we have once a month
我们可以和其他合作伙伴进行视频聊天，合作伙伴是我的patreon上的赞助人支持
where we actually just have a video chat with all the other partners, partner is a tier of patreon support on my patreon
我们实际上在讨论这个领域的发展方向，以及如何做事情
we actually have a discussion about where this area is going, and how to do things
我想这实际上是在去年11月的时候发生的
and this actually came out I think at the last month partner hang out in november
所以如果你们感兴趣的话，一定要去看看，但我必须做出让步
so definitely check that out, if you're interested, but I have to make compromises
因为我必须在娱乐教育和软件工程之间做出妥协
because I have to compromise between entertainment education and soft engineering
但无论如何，我现在决定创建一个窗口，我认为现在是一个好时机
but anyway, I've decided to make a window kind of now, I think now is a good point
我们至少有日志和事件，在我看来，这些东西就像一个桅杆，在你们创建一个窗口之前
we at least have logging and we have events, that stuff is like a mast in my opinion before you make a window
因为我的意思是，这并不重要，你们可以先创建你们的窗口，然后再创建其他系统
because I mean, it doesn't really matter, you can make your window first, and then make the other systems
但它们是相辅相成的，你们需要日志记录，因为需要看到发生了什么，如果事情出错了
but they go hand in hand, you need logging, because you need to see what's happening, if things go wrong
当你们在写Window类的时候，能插入日志，像断言之类的东西是很好的
and as you're kind of writing your Window class, it's nice to be able to insert logging, and like assertions and stuff
实际上，我们今天也讨论了断言，但是还需要事件，因为窗口与事件绑定得非常紧密
we actually talk about assertions closely today as well, but you also want events, because a window is very tiredly tied with events
我们今天会看一下如何以抽象的方式实现Window类
and we're just going to take a look at actually implementing kind of a Window class today in an abstract way
记住，我们想要支持多个平台，而窗口在其他平台上的实现会有所不同
because remember, we want to support multiple platforms, and the implementation of windows on those other platforms will actually kind of differ
所以我们想要一个窗口的抽象表示，这是我们今天会讲到的，然后还有事件之类的东西
so we want an abstract presentation of a Window, which we'll talk about today, and then also stuff like events
我想我们会在下一集讲到，我们可以把窗口系统连接到所有的事件
I think we'll cover in the next episode, we can actually hook up our window system to all of our events
让那个正确地运行，让我们谈谈技术，他们想要使用一点
and just have that kind of work correctly, let's talk about the technology, they want to use a little bit
所以我将使用一个叫做GLFW的库，我有一个OpenGL系列
so I'm going to use a library called GLFW, I have an OpenGL series
我有一个关于GLFW的视频，这可能会比今天的视频中更详细
and I have a video about GLFW, which will probably be more detailed in today's video
我想假设你们知道如何使用它，GLFW是一个非常非常简单的跨平台
I want to assume that you guys kind of know how to use that, GLFW is a very very simple kind of cross platform
跨平台意味着，像Windows, MacOS，我认为他们可能也支持其他平台
cross platform meaning, like Windows, MacOS, I think they support maybe other platforms as well
但这是创建窗口的简单方法，使用相关平台接口创建窗口
but it's just a really easy way to kind of create a window, a window using your relevant platform api
我真的不想花太多时间来使用Win32API来创建一个窗口
I don't really want to take too much time to actually use the Win32API to create a window
只是因为这不是这个系列的真正内容，我们我们最终可能不得不这样做
just because not what this series is really about, we we might eventually have to
因为你们知道的，例如GLFW实际上并不支持DirectX，对吧
because you know, GLFW, for example doesn't actually support DirectX, right
在某些时候，我们可能希望在Hazel中支持DirectX
we probably want to support DirectX in Hazel at some point
因为那是我在Windows上首选的渲染接口
because that's my preferred rendering platform on Windows
它应该是每个人在Windows上首选的渲染接口，因为它是微软为Windows开发的
and it should be everyone's preferred rendering api on Windows, because it's made by Microsoft for Windows
所以显然，当你们在Windows上运行时，它会比其他接口更好
so obviously, it's going to be better than any other api, when you're running on Windows
话虽如此，我还是想让一些东西运行起来
that being said, I do want to get something up and running
我想我提到过，我们会在一开始坚持使用OpenGL
and I think I mentioned that, we're gonna stick to OpenGL in the beginning
这样我们就能尽快得到东西，因此我们陷入了两难境地
just so that we can get stuff as quickly as possible, so because of that we have kind of a dilemma
所以我现在不想浪费时间写Win32API，但将来我们可能不得不写
so I don't want to waste time now writing Win32API, but we might have to in the future
还有GLFW，它可以在多个平台上使用
and also GLFW something that's available on multiple platforms
所以我们马上就会想到，抽象在哪里
so immediately we kind of have to think about, well where does the abstraction lie
我选择做的是为每个平台实现一个Window类
what I've chosen to do is to implement a Window class per platform
现在你们可能会想，等一下，如果使用GLFW
now you might be like well hang on,  if you're using GLFW
在Windows, Mac和Linux上的实现不是很大程度上是一样的吗
isn't the implementation going to be largely the same on Windows, Mac and Linux
是的，一开始可能是这样的，或者是相似的，可能有一些细微的不同
well yes initially it probably will be, or it will be similar, maybe there's some slight differences
一些我们可能想添加的东西，比如只在Windows上，或者可能在其他平台上有所不同
some stuff that we might wanna add, that's on Windows only for example, or that might differ on other platforms
但GLFW当然是一样的，因为作为GLFW，它是抽象到其他类型的平台
but GLFW, guys of course it's going to be the same, because as a glfw, is that abstraction away into the other kind of platforms
所以我仍然会为每个平台创建一个单独的Window类
so I'm still going to make a separate Window class per platform
然而，我想这是我们第一次把东西抽象出来，我们也会讲到那个
however, and I think this is the first time we're actually abstracting stuff, so we'll talk about that as well
但是在未来，我们可能会，就像你们知道的，在Windows上的GLFW，我将放弃它
however in the future, we might be, like you know, GLFW on Windows, I'm dropping that
因为我们将要切换到使用Win32API，因为需要创建一个DirectX上下文等等
because we're actually going to switch to using Win32API, because we need to make a DirectX contents and all of that
我的意思是，我们可以修改GLFW来实现这一点
I mean we could modify GLFW potentially to do that
或者我们可以只获得所需的Win32，像hz_window_handles之类的东西
or we could just get the required Win32, like hz_window_handles, and stuff like that
和设备句柄一样，设备上下文处理GLFW，它用来创建窗口
and like the device handles, the device context handles from GLFW, which it uses to create the windows
使用Win32API创建窗口，不论如何，然后从那里，我们将有我们的必要的句柄
Window using the Win32API anyway, and then from there, we would have our necessary handles
我们需要创建一个DirectX上下文，但我还没有决定，但重点是肯定会有一个重点
that we need to actually create a DirectX context, but I haven't decided yet, but the point is there's definitely gonna be a point
但我们只做窗口的创建代码之类的东西，对吧
but we do Windows only Windows creation code and all that stuff, right
所以我们肯定想要一个Windows类型的窗口
so we definitely want a Windows kind of window
即使我们使用的是GLFW，希望跨平台，希望这是有意义的
even though we're using GLFW, wishes cross platforms, hopefully that makes sense
我还修改了，我还把GLFW分支拷贝到我自己的私人报告到我自己的github仓库
um I've also modified, I've also forked GLFW into my own private report into my own github repository
它是公共的，只是cherno，它是github.com/TheCherno/glfw，我们马上就会使用它
it's public, it's just TheCherno, it's github.com/TheCherno/glfw, will use it here in a minute
我刚刚添加了premake，一个非常快速的premake文件，目前只在Windows上运行
I've just added premake to it, just a really quick premake file, that only works on Windows for now
我可能会在未来更新它以支持更多的平台
I'll probably update that in the future to support more platforms as well
但有一个简单的方法来整合GLFW与我们的premake，同时有GLFW
but there's just an easy way to integrate GLFW with our premake build whilst having GLFW
我们visual studio解决方案中的所有源代码，然后链接到项目中
all the source code in our visual studio solution and all of that, and then just link it kind of project
为什么，这也是我所做的，我想我们可以谈谈
why so that's what I've done as well, and I think we can probably talk about
关于抽象平台的概念以及它的原理，我可能会专门做一个视频来介绍
just the notion of platform abstraction and how that works, I'll probably make a video dedicated to that
因为今天我只想得到一个窗口，如果我开始谈论这个
because today I just want to get a window up and running, and if I start talking about this
它最终会占据整集，但本质上我做的是创建了一个平台文件夹
it's going to end up taking up the whole episode, but essentially what I've done is I made a platform folder
这是针对特定平台的代码
which is for platform specific code
然后我创建了一个Windows文件夹，这是针对Windows代码的，对吧
and then I've made a Windows folder, which is for Windows code, right
我们最终也会有一个Mac和Linux文件夹
we'll also have eventually a Mac and Linux folder
也许如果我们支持移动平台，Android iOS之类的东西
and maybe if we support mobile platforms, Android iOS that kind of stuff
在平台文件夹中，我们也将放置渲染接口特定代码，如OpenGL, DirectX, Valkan, Metal
and in the platform folder, we'll also lie our rendering api specific codes, such as OpenGL, DirectX, Valkan, Metal
这些东西也会有自己的文件夹，我们甚至会有一个正面文件夹
that kind of stuff will also have its own folder there, we might even have a positive folder
这只是一种Mac分析相关和Android相关的代码，如果它们最终是相同的
that's just kind of Mac analytics related and Android related code, if it ends up being the same
但那就是你们需要知道的关于平台抽象的全部内容
but that's kind of the idea, that's all you need to know about platform abstraction
现在，让我们继续添加我已经fork为子模块的GLFW存储库
now let's go ahead and add the GLFW repository that I've forked as a submodule now
这样我们就可以把它放到我们的项目中，好了，我这里有，你们可以看到
so that we can actually get it into our project, okay, so what I have here is, as you can see
TheCherno/GLFW，我想我刚刚把它从GLFW中分出来
TheCherno/GLFW, I've just forked it from GLFW a while ago I think
因为你们可以看到，它落后master分支有11个提交
because you can see, it's 11 commits behind master
但它只是拷贝GLFW的master分支，然后我所做的就是添加了这个
but it's just fork from GLFW master, and then what all I've done is I've added this
这实际上是28天前，哇哦，4周前，我加了这个premake脚本
this is actually 28 days ago, wow four weeks ago, I added this premake
所以你们可以看到，赞助人可以访问的Hazel dev分支的距离有多远
so you can see, how much, how far aheaf the Hazel dev repository is which patrons get access to
因为这是我四周前做的，但无论如何，这个premake5.lua文件很简单，对吧
because I did this actually like four weeks ago, but anyway, this premake5.lua file very simple, right
它有45行代码，所有这些都是为Windows做的
it's 45 lines of code, all this does is just for Windows essentially for now
我认为意图有点错误，但无论如何，这个东西甚至不能运行，这需要更新到最新
intentation I think is a bit wrong, but anyway, this stuff doesn't even work, and this needs to be updated to latest
有一些事情需要做，实际上我认为，我以为我推送了，但我没有
and there's a few things that need to be done, actually I thought, I thought I pushed that, but I didn't
这个？很糟糕，但无论如何，你们可以看到，在Windows过滤中，包含了所有相关文件
so yeah the invitation is horrible, but anyway, you can see it includes all the relevant files here on the filter windows
这些都是平台无关的平台独立文件，这些是Windows专用文件
these are all the platform agnostic kind of platform independent files, these are the Windows only files
然后它也有定义，所有这些东西都很简单，什么都没有
and then it's got defines as well, and all that stuff really simple, stuff nothing really to it
我们将把它克隆为一个子模块，因为它包括我们的premake文件以及所有的GLFW
we're going to clone this as a sub module, because this includes our premake file as well as all of GLFW
所以我想在c:\dev\Hazel使用命令提示符，这是仓库的路径
so I want to command prompt in c:\dev\Hazel, which is our kind of repository route
也就是git submodule add，然后添加glfw子模块
I'm just going to say, I've been git submodule add, I'm going to add this glfw submodule
并且把它添加到Hazel/vendor/GLFW，好了，它会把整个仓库克隆到那个目录中
and I want to add to Hazel/vendor/GLFW, okay, and it's going to clone this whole repository into that directory
然后如果我们启动这个，我们应该看到在vendor里面，现在有GLFW，对吧
and then if we kind of boot this up, we should see inside vendor, we now have GLFW, okay
里面有我们版本的GLFW和premake，所以现在要做的是添加一个我们自己的premake
and that has our version of GLFW along with that premake file, so now what we want to do is actually add a to our premake file
我已经做过了，所以我要给你们展示一下不同之处，实际上我们只做一个git
and I've already done that, so I will just show you the differences, in fact we'll just do a git
就是git difftool --dir，好了，这就是全部内容，让我们看看premake文件文件
we'll do a difftool dir, okay, so this is all of it, let's look at the premake file file
所以这就是我对premake文件所做的，实际上最终创建了一个结构，一个较低的表
so this is what I've done to the premake file, I actually ended up creating basically a struct, a lower table
这将是一个包含目录的列表，那些不是我们的
which is going to be a list of include directories that we have, that aren't ours
现在这些都很重要，因为我们想要在Hazel中有GLFW include目录
now these are important, because we want to obviously have GLFW include directory, you know, in Hazel
这样我们就可以使用glfw/glfw.h，它必须包含，所以我设置了一个编译器包含目录
so that we can just use glfw/glfw.h, which will have to include, so I'm setting a compiler include directory
但我只是把它放到了它自己的结构中放到了它自己的表中，因为它会增长
but I've just put it into its own kind of struct here into its own table, because this will grow
显然要包含每个依赖项
obviously to include each dependency
至于这里这个include，实际上包含我们的premake文件，那么也就是这个premake
this include here, actually includes that premake file that we have, so this premake file
你们知道，我们刚刚看了这个，这个目录是Hazel/vendor/GLFW，好了，包含这个
you know, we just looked at this, this directory is Hazel/vendor/GLFW, okay, I'm including this
它的作用是将premake5文件包含到这里，所以基本上这就像一个cpp风格的包含
which what this will do is include that premake5 file into here, so basically this is almost like a cpp style include where this
如果我们在VS中看看这个，这个会被复制并粘贴到我们的premake5文件中，对吧
if we look at this in Visual Studio, this kind of gets copied and pasted into our premake5 file, right
所以在我们的premake文件中，我们现在有另一个项目叫做GLFW，你们可以看到
so inside our premake file, we now have another project called GLFW, you can see
它没有工作空间或类似的东西，它没有工作空间GLFW，它没有解决方案
this does not have workspace or anything like that, it doesn't have workspace GLFW, it doesn't have a solution
它只是一个项目，只是一个附加项目，它作为静态库输出编译到相同的目录中
it's just a project, just an additional project, which compiles as a static library outputs into the same directory
它只包含一些文件，好了，就是那样，我们刚刚添加的另一个项目
and it just includes a bunch of files, okay, that's all it is, we've just added another project
重要的是，一旦我们有了这个项目，我们就会把它直接链接到我们的Hazel项目上
and then the important thing is once we have that project, we're actually going to link it right to our Hazel project
所以Hazel现在依赖于GLFW，Hazel是一个共享库，这意味着它是一个dll文件
so Hazel is now dependent on GLFW, Hazel is a shared library, meaning it's a dll file
当然，我们可以只包含一个静态库，或者链接一个静态库
so of course we can just include a static library into it, right, or link rather a static library into it
我们需要修复别人的一个缩进，我不知道，那么糟糕的是，当你们不知道会发生什么
we need to fix others in an indentation, I did not know, so bad this is, what happens when you don't
让我们来看看这个，我们去查看，这个在哪里
let's look at this for a minute, and let's go to view, and where is this
我认为这是一个没有高级编辑和空白的视图，这样我们就能看到到底发生了什么
I think it's a view no edit advanced and view white space, just so we can see what on earth is going on
你可以看到，这是制表符，这是空格，这就是为什么它很乱，所以我要把这些都转换成空格
so you can see, this is tabs, and this is spaces, that's why it's messing up, so I'm just going to convert all of this to spaces
这应该会让一切变得更好，因为很明显，在这个文件中使用空格的地方
and this should make everything a lot better, because clearly where mostly using spaces in this file
我认为这也是一个标签
I think that's no this is a tab as well
好了，这个东西也是，它很有用，如果你们想像这样解决问题
okay, and so is this stuff, so it's quite useful, if you want to fix stuff up like this
好了，我们可以删掉这个，很好，现在如果我们刷新这个，一切应该会更好
okay, we can get rid of that, okay, brilliant, so now if we refresh this, everything should be better
它不在那里，这是在困难上，它出于某种原因是临时的，让我们重新运行difftool
it's not there, this is on difficult, it's made a temporary for some reason, so let's just rerun difftool
我们应该看到，这是完美的，但显然不是，这是正确的文件，我认为是GLFW，哎呀
and we should see, this is now perfect, but it's clearly not, it's just the right file, I think GLFW, whoops
好吧，我们来解决GLFW的问题，我们也来解决我们的问题，因为这显然是一团糟
okay, so we fix the GLFW one, let's fix our one as well, because this is apparently a mess
哦，哇，这是标签，我看到了，这是旧标签
oh wow, so this is mercily tabs, I see, about this is old tabs
好吧，这是空格，我们需要使用制表符或空格，不要同时使用两个
okay, this is spaces though, wow okay, we need to really stick to tabs or spaces, and not use both
因为这有点拖后腿，无论如何，我认为这应该很好，我们现在到处都有标签
because this is a bit of a drag, anyway, I think that should be good, we've got tabs everywhere now
好了，那么已经修复了那个，所以我们需要重新启动，因为它在临时目录中
okay, so does that fix it, so we have to restart this again, because it is in a temporary directory
好了，很好，现在好了，那么回到这里，我们把GLFW连接起来
and there we go, good, it's good now, okay, so back to this, so we're linking GLFW
就是我们刚刚提到的那个项目，对吧
which is that project that we've just included, okay
这个IncludeDir只需要添加为编译器的包含目录，这就是我们在这里所做的
now this IncludeDir just needs to get added as a compiler include directory, which is what we've done here
现在包含目录，我们的包含目录，我们添加了%\
now included directories, and our include directories, we've added include directory GLFW
这意味着，Hazel/vendor/GLFW/include现在是一个编译器包含目录
which means that, Hazel/vendor/GLFW/include is now a compiler include directory
好了，那就是我所做的所有更改
okay, and that's all the changes that I've made
所以要包含那个premake文件，然后设置包含目录和链接
so literally include that premake file, and then just set the include directory and the link
我们还链接openl32.lib，因为我们需要那个，那就是我所做的，好了
we're also linking openl32.lib, because we need that, that's all that I've done, okay
现在让我们看看我添加的一些新文件实际上，首先让我们运行premake
now let's take a look at some of the new files that I've added actually, well first thing let's just run premake
因为我还没有运行premake，我们会执行GenerateProject，然后希望我们会做所有这些
because I haven't even ran premake yet, so we'll do GenerateProject, and then hopefully we'll do all that
你们可以看到，它生成了GLFW项目，如果我们回到VS重载，它就是解决方案
you can see, it's generate that GLFW project, if we go back to visual studio reload, it's the solution
我们应该在这里看到GLFW，你们应该看到Hazel实际上引用了GLFW，好了，漂亮
we should see GLFW here, and you should see that Hazel actually references GLFW, okay, beautiful
让我们试着在调试x64中编译它，希望这能成功编译，我还没有这么做
let's try and compile that in debug x64, hopefully this compils successfully, I haven't actually done this
好吧，有一些未知的选择，我会在GLFW里把它清理掉
okay, so there's some unknown options, I'll clean that up in the GLFW thing
我不知道，这只是尝试使用c11，这不是用于VS编译的
I don't know, this is just trying to use c11 brothers here, this is not for visual studio compiler
因为它在链接上的方式，这或多或少，可能clang或GCC都可能接受这个
because of the way that it's on linking, this is more or less for, probably clang or gcc would probably both accept this
但很明显，MSVC编译器中的命令行参数有不同的语法
but obviously there's a different syntax for command line arguments in the MSVC compiler
不管怎样，一个的成功就是忽略这些，那很好，我们现在已经构建了GLFW
anyway, one succeeded is just ignoring those, that was fine, and we've now built GLFW
你们可以看到，这是多么简单，所以我喜欢premake，因为它很好，很容易使用，好了
you can see, how easy that was, so I love premake, because it's so nice and easy to use, okay
那么下一步，让我们看一下我创建的一些Window类，在Hazel中，就在Hazel中
so next step, let's take a look at some of the Window classes that I've made, so inside Hazel, just inside Hazel
你们可以看到，这里也有一个Platform目录，但在Hazel中，我有这个Window类
you can see there's a Platform folder as well, but inside Hazel itself, I have this Window class now
并且这是Window的抽象表示，好了，所以这是平台无关的
and this is an abstract representation of a Window, okay, so this is platform independent
这是我们的Application所使用的，如果没看到的话
this is what our application uses, haven't read it yet
我会在你们面前写，Application还没有被修改
I'll write in front of you guys, Application hasn't been modified yet
但我们基本上会使用这个Window，好了，你们可以看到它有些什么
but we're basically going to use this Window, okay, and you can see what it has
它有一个EventCallbackFn，我们会在下一期讲，它增加了一个虚析构函数
now, it's got an EventCallbackFn,  which we'll talk about in the next episode, added a virtual destructor
然后它基本上就像你们看到的那样，它实际上只是一个接口，所有这些都是纯虚拟方法
and then it's mostly as you can see pretty much, it's it's all actually just an interface, right, all of these are pure virtual methods
这个类中没有任何数据，也没有任何函数，都是纯虚方法，对吧
there's no data in this class at all, and there's no functions in this class at all, just pure virtual stuff, right
因为这需要在每个平台上实现，所以我只做了一个接口，对吧
because this has to be implemented per platform, so I've just made an interface, okay
当然是桌面系统，因为以移动应用为例，它并没有真正的窗口
a desktop system of course, because mobile apps for example, don't really have a window
它们总想要有一个表面，好了，这是基本的，随着我们的进行，不会添加太多东西到它上面
they want to always have a surface, okay, so that's that, okay, kind of basic, not much will add stuff to it, as we go
但就是那样的，然后至于这个，我有一些基本的窗口属性
but that's just what it is, and then this, I just have some basic window properties
你们可以在这里指定，因为这是平台无关的
which you can specify over here, now because this is kind of platform independent this
我们有这个Create函数，它必须在每个平台上实现
we have this create function, which actually has to be implemented per platform
所以这儿没有Window.cpp文件，只有一个Window.h文件，一个头文件
so this is not, there's no Window.cpp file, there's just a Window file, just a header file
然后这个会在每个平台上实现，因为显然这个Create函数会返回
and then this gets implemented per platform, because obviously this create  function should return
例如WindowsWindow，如果我们在Windows或MAC窗口或Linux窗口上编译
for example WindowsWindow, if we're compiling on windows or mac window or linux window
或者我们决定怎么称呼它取决于我们在哪个平台上编译
or whatever we decide to call it depending on what platform we're actually compiling on
例如，这儿不需要有一个独立于平台的switch声明
there's no need to for example have a platform independent one, which has a switch statement
其中包括，它不，这都是编译时决定的
which includes, it doesn't, this is all decided to compile time
不管怎样，我们不会在Windows或其他版本上编译Mac代码，属性就是Title，Width和Height
anyway, we're not going to be compiling Mac code on windows or vice version, property is Title Width Height
那就是我们现在得到的，这里还有默认有效的默认参数
that's all we've got for now, default valid default parameters here as well
Hazel Engine是默认标题，如果你们不指定的话，然后在高度范围内的默认值是720
Hazel engine is the default title, if you don't specify one, and then to our value by 720 is the default within height
然后你们可以看到，如果不指定一个作为属性，它会创建默认值，也就是这个
and then you can see, we have, if you don't specify one as properties, it creates the default, which is this
好了，就是那样，在Platform/Windows里面，我们有WindowsWindow，还有cpp文件
okay, that's that, now inside Platform, inside Windows, we have WindowsWindow, and the cpp file as well, okay
这很简单，这只是所有东西的实现，对吧
this is pretty simple, this is just an implementation of everything, okay
那么有些函数应该标记为override，我不知道为什么没有
so some of this stuff actually really should be marked as override, I don't know why it's not
所以让我们看看它到底继承了什么
so let's see what it actually inherits
VSync然后是EventCallback，Width，Height和OnUpdate
so VSync and then EventCallback Width Height and OnUpdate
所以说，我只是忘了这两个，好吧
so that's all said, I just miss these two apparently, okay
那么这个实现的主要方式是我们有一个WindowData结构，你们会看到为什么我们有这个
so the way that this is primarily implemented is we have a struct of WindowData, you'll see why we have this
因为我们需要将它传递给GLFW，但这或多或少是用于事件的，不管怎样，将在下期中讨论
because we need to pass it into GLFW, but that's more or less for events, which we'll talk about next time anyway
但这是我们存储所有实际数据的地方，这些数据可能在事件回调期间被GLFW请求
but basically this is where we store all of our actual data, that might be requested by GLFW during event callbacks
然后我们就有了一个结构
and then we just have a struct
这样我们就可以把这个结构传递给GLFW，就像用户自定义数据一样
this way we can pass just the struct to GLFW, as like custom user data
我们不需要通过这个类，这不是很重要
and we don't have to pass this entire class, not that it matters too much
但这只是让我们所有的Windows专门的数据很好地集中在这里
but this just keeps all of our kind of Windows special data grouped nicely here
我有点喜欢我们有Init和Shutdown，也就是我们创建的两种函数
which I kind, which I kind of like we have Init and Shutdown, which is two kind of functions that we've created
在OnUpdate中，我们会更新GLFW，而缓冲区会轮询输入事件，诸如此类的东西
OnUpdate, we'll just kind of should just update GLFW, while the buffers polling the input events all that kind of stuff
它应该按帧运行一次，并从我们的Application中调用，我们马上就会调用它
it should be run like once by frame, and called from our application, we'll call that in a minute
其他一切都很简单，让我们跳到实现
everything else I think is pretty straightforward, let's pop over to the implementation
那么这就是我们在Window中Create函数的实现
so here's the implementation of that creation function that we had in windows and window
我们有了这个Create函数，它是在平台特定文件中实现的
we had this create function, was this actually gets implemented in a platform specific file
那么在这里，它实现了，它是Window::Create()，而不是WindowsWindow::Create()
so in this case, it's implemented,  you can see, it's Window::Create, not WindowsWindow::Create
只创建窗口并返回一个新的WindowsWindow，好了，就那样，很简单，只返回一个指针
just window create, and returns a new WindowsWindow, okay, that's it, pretty simple, it just returns a pointer, okay
我们将把这个指针存储在实际Application类中的一个惟一指针中
we'll store this pointer in probably a unique pointer in the actual Application class
好了，那么在初始化和析构函数中暂时什么都不做，这只是导致它
okay, so in the in the initialization destructor does nothing for now, this just causing it
我还没有在析构函数中做任何事情的原因是我们不需要这么做
we the reason I don't I haven't done anything in the destructor yet is because we not don't necessarily need to
我们实际上可以销毁窗口，我想应该是glfwDestoryWindow()，我们应该这样做并关闭窗口
we can destroy the window actually, I think glfwDestroyWindow, we should do that and shut down
我们现在就添加这段代码，也就是Shutdown()，可以那样做，但我们不想关闭GLFW
let's just add that code right now um, Shutdown, we can do that, but we don't want to necessarily shut down GLFW
因为我们可能，我们可能需要它，我们可能有多个窗口，这也是我这里有这个静态的原因
because we might, we might need it, like we might have more than one window, that's also why I have this static here
因为我们只想在初始化Window时初始化GLFW一次，但我们可能会创建多个Window
because we only want to initialize GLFW, once when we initialize our Window, but we might create multiple windows
但如果它还没有初始化，我们会初始化它
so yeah, but if it's not, if it hasn't been initialized yet, we'll initialize it
所以这就是它的作用，当我们创建这个Window时，它调用构造函数
so this is that's essentially what in it does, when we create this window, it calls the constructor
调用它设置基于属性的数据，记录些可能想要看到的东西，初始化GLFW，如果它还没有
which calls in it sets up all about data based on the properties, logs some stuff that we might want to see, initializes GLFW, if it hasn't yet
然后我们来说说这个HZ_CORE_ASSERT()，因为那是新东西，在Core.h中
and then let's talk about this CORE_ASSERT, because that's new, inside Core.h
我添加了断言，如果我们启用它们
I've added assertions, if we enabled them
好了，我们应该把它添加到premake文件中以便调试，可能还没发布
okay, we should add that to the premake file for debug probably, probably not released
它做的基本上是，它检查一个特定的条件，然后记录一条消息，如果它失败了
what this does is basically it says, it checks a certain condition, and then logs a message, if it fails
而且它的Windows现在只会导致调试中断
and also its Windows only for now, just cause debug break
这就像在这行代码上设置断点一样
which basically just is like in setting a breakpoint at that line of code
这样它就会在这行代码中中断调试器，如果断言失败
so that it just breaks the debugger on this actual line of code, okay, so that if an assertion fails
我们可以看到哪里出错了，例如在这个例子中，我们在这里用它来检查这个是否行
we can see what has gone wrong, okay, so for example in this case, we're using it here to check to see if this has worked out
那么如果这是在运行时删除的东西，抱歉，在发布版本或发行版本中
so if this is something that gets removed in runtime, sorry in like release builds for example or distribution builds
那就是为什么我没有像这样写代码，因为如果发生了这种情况
that's why I didn't write this code like this, for example, because if that happened
那么GLFW将不会在发布版本中被初始化
then GLFW would not be initialized at all in release builds
这不是我们想要的，我们仍然希望被初始化，但我们只是在调试构建中检查条件
which is not what we want, we still wanted to be initialized, but we're just checking the condition only in debug builds
我们可以添加一个叫做verify的东西，而不是assert，它基本上和assert是一样的
we might add something called verify instead of assert, which basically is the same as an assert
但是它没有去掉条件，所以它基本上是这样做的，原因是它可以
except it doesn't strip the condition, so it basically does that instead, the reason is that this can
因为在某些配置中，如果启用会话是关闭的，那么这将不会编译成任何东西
because this compiles to nothing at all in like certain configurations, if enable sessions is off
我们可以运行在其他情况下根本不会运行的函数，来验证一些东西，所以这很有用
we can run functions that we wouldn't otherwise run at all, just to verify stuff, so it's quite useful
断言是会被大量使用的东西，我喜欢使用它们
and assertions are just something that will be using a lot of, I love using them
这是一种验证状态是否正确的快速方法，而且在这样做时，你们不必担心会浪费性能
just a quick way to verify that your state is correct, and you don't have to worry about wasting performance, when you do that
因为它们被从发布版本中去掉，然后至于glfwCreateWindow()
because they get stripped from release builds, we glfwCreateWindow
再说一次，我的OpenGL系列中的GLFW视频可能会对此有更多解释
again, that GLFW video in my OpenGL series will probably explain more about this
但基本上只是创建了一个GLFW窗口，调用MakeContextCurrent，设置WindowUserPointer
but we basically just create a glfw window, MakeContextCurrent and set a WindowUserPointer
这是我们会在m_Data的事件回调中用到的，因为当我们
now this is something that we'll use in our event callbacks for m_Data, because when we
但GLFW的原理就是那样，我们只设置特定的事件回调
but the way the GLFW works is that, we just set certain event callbacks
例如glfwSetKeyCallbacl()，这只是一个我们指定的回调函数
for example GLFW set, you know, a key callback, and this is just a callback function that we specify
每当我们按下一个键，它都会被调用
that will get called, whenever we press a key
这意味着我们将这个结构数据或指定给这个数据结构到回调函数
this means that we are passing this struct data or appointed to this struct of data into that callback function
例如，我可以调用那个事件回调函数
so that we can for example be like I can call that event callback function
如果一个键被按下，或者如果窗口大小改变，我可以设置宽高，也可以调用回调
if if a key is pressed, or if the window size changes, I can set this width and high, and also call the callback
所以那就是我们设置这个的目的，然后我们认为我们已经把它设为真了
so that's kind of what we set this for; and then we think we've just set it true
因为没有理由关闭它，关闭它会破坏窗口，我们认为
because there's no reason really for it to be off, shut down destroys the window, we decided that
至于更新，我们只需要轮询事件并交换缓冲区，然后我们还有一个SetVSync函数
now update, we'll just poll the events and swap the buffers, and then we have a SetVSync function which
如果我们决定启用VSync，它说切换到4:1，这实际上不一定是1
if we decide to enable a VSync, it says to swap into four to one, this doesn't actually have to be one
1只是意味着它会等待一个帧被调用，一个帧被返回，因为它开始的时候就像下一帧
one just means it'll wait for like one frame to be called, one frame to be returned bigger, for it starts like the next thing
0没有任何意义，所以那就是我们现在所做的
where zero means nothing, so that's what we've done for now
再说一次，我想一个支持替换Win32代码的地方，实际上可能是一些不同的东西
again I imagine one support of places with with Win32 code, will actually might be something a bit different
但那只是装饰的一个基本实现，然后我们跟踪它是否被启用
but that's just a basic implementation of facing, and then we keep track of whether or on it's enabled
因为我们无法从GLFW中获取数据，然后我们只有一个简单的IsVSync函数
because we can't actually retrieve that data from GLFW, and then we just we have an IsVSync function
它会在它们打开时返回也就是打开，好了，就那样，那就是我们的窗口，很简单吧
which returns while they're on that is switched on, okay, that's it, that's our window, really simple stuff
让我们把它添加到我们的Application中，那么我要做的就是在Application中
let's add this to our our Application now, so what I'm going to do is inside Application
再说一次，这是平台无关的，我要创建一个唯一指针，它将保存Window类的一个实例
again, this is platform independent, I'm going to create a unique pointer, which is going to hold an instance of the Window class
至于唯一指针，因为很明显只有这个类拥有它，这里应该包含Window.h
unique, because obviously only this class owns it, this will be just Window.h
我们有Window的唯一指针，然后在构造函数中，我们会把它设为
so we have a unique pointer of Window, and then all we do is in the constructor, we'll set this to be
我们不会创建唯一指针之类的，这个应该就是Window::Create()
we're not gonna make unique or anything, it's just gonna be window, create window, or window to create window create
我们可能不会指定属性，因为这是一个显式构造函数
and we'll specify probably no properties, now because this is an explicit constructor
我们需要在这里输入唯一指针，然后像那样使用Window::Create()来创建它，好了，酷
we actually have to type unique pointer here, and then do WindowCreate like that to create it, okay, cool
那么我们就得到了那个，有了我们的唯一指针
so we've got that, we've got our unique pointer
意味着当应用程序终止时，我们不需要自己删除窗口
means we don't have to delete the window ourselves, when the application terminates
我们的Application显然是一种单例，意味着我们整个应用程序只有一个Application
we Application obviously is kind of a Singleton, meaning we only have one Application for our entire application
所以这个一定不错，好了，那我们暂时先去掉这些事件测试
so this is definitely fine, okay, we'll get rid of all this kind of event testing for now
然后在这儿，我要创建一个布尔属性m_Running，我们可能一开始就把它设为true
and then inside here, I'm actually going to make a bool here, called Running, which we're probably set to true to begin with
我们可以在这里初始化它，所以当它运行时
we can just initialize it here, so while this is running
我们会通过调用m_Window.OnUpdate()来更新窗口
we're going to update our window by calling m_Window.OnUpdate
我的意思是我们可以在这里签入一些OpenGL代码来测试它
and I mean we could just check in some OpenGL code here to test it in a minute
但那应该是我们需要做的所有事情
but that should be all we need to do really
因为Window::Create()会调用构造函数，构造函数会调用Init()，Init()会创建初始化的GLFW
because Window::Create will call the constructor, which will call Init, which will actually create initialized GLFW
以及创建窗口，实际上，那应该很不错
and create out windows, that actually should be good
所以如果我们按f5或这里的play按钮来调试代码，我们会看到什么
so if we hit f5 or the play button here just to actually debug our code, we'll see what happens
这显然是第一次构建GLFW链接，所以希望一切都正常
and this is obviously building a linking GLFW for the first time, so hopefully everything works out
好了，看看，那么我们看到了Hazel Engine，它说我们创建了一个窗口，也就是Hazel引擎
okay, check that out, so we have Hazel Engine here over here, it says that we've created a window, which is our Hazel engine
我可以删掉这个App Hello，也可以保留它，因为它在测试客户端日志
I might just get rid of this App Hello, maybe we can keep it there, because it's testing um client side logging
但是你们可以看到的是，创建窗口，Hazel Engine (1280, 720)
but yeah create window Hazel Engine 1280 by 720, you can see, it's there
我们不能关闭它，因为还没有相应的处理事件
we can't close it or anything, because we're not handling events yet
那将在下一期讲到，但我们得到了这个，很好，不过还应该有一个OpenGL上下文
that will be in the next episode, but we have this, awesome, and we should also have an OpenGL context
所以我们现在应该能做的是，也就是在这个文件中包含glfw3
so what we should be able to do is for now I'll be naughty and include glfw3 in this file
但我现在能做的就是调用glClearColor(1, 0, 1, 1)，也就是粉红色，洋红色？
and I'll just do something like glClearColor(1, 0, 1, 1), which is pink, oh magenta
然后我们来调用glClear(GL_COLOR_BUFFER_BIT)
and then we'll just call glClear on the COLOR_BUFFER_BIT
好了，让我们看看这是否有效，应该会得到一个粉红色的窗口
okay, let's see if this works, we should get a pink window here
很好，就是那样，好了，那么我们终于有了一个窗口，和一个OpenGL上下文，还没有事件
awesome, there you go, okay, so we have now a window finally, and an OpenGL context, no events yet
所以我们想要的是下一步我将从这里开始
so we want the next step kind of where I would go from here
实际上也就是创建键盘事件，鼠标事件以及窗口事件
is to actually make it, so that key events and mouse events and window events
比如关闭和调整大小所有这些有趣的东西实际上都会传递到这个Application类
like closing and resizing and all of that fun stuff is actually propagated to this Application class
所以本质上我们想要的是一个函数，类似于OnEvent，对吧
so essentially what we want to have is a function here, which is like OnEvent, right
至于OnEvent函数，当我们调用它时，我们会从Window类中调用它
and OnEvent function, which when we call, which we will kind of call from the Window class
但我们显然不希望Window类知道Application的存在
but we obviously don't want the Window class to be aware of Application at all
应该完全模块化，不应该依赖于Application
should be completely modular and kind of out the side, should not depend on application at all
那就是为什么有一个SetEventCallback函数的原因，我们会从Application来通知Window
which is why we have a SetEventCallback function, which we'll just kind of call from the Application to notify the Window
嘿，所有的事件请把它们调用回这里，然后我们可以把它们传递到所有关于层的地方
hey, all the events please call them back into here, and then we can propagate them to all about layers
并且那就是这个引擎处理各种事件的方式，包括窗口事件
and that is how this engine will basically deal with events of any kind, including window events
所以下一次，我们会实现它，我真的很兴奋
so next time, we'll implement that, that I'm really excited about that
我想如果我们只是看看这些差异，我不认为我漏掉了什么
I think if we just look at the different, I don't think I've missed anything
我唯一做过的其他改动就是，修改了pch，哦，是的，我把log添加到pch文件中
the only other stuff I did, I modify the pch, oh yeah I added the log to the pch file
因为日志不会改变，这是我们在每个文件中都想要的
because logs are not gonna change, and this is something we want in pretty much every file
以及在Core.h中，做了一个断言，就像我之前提到的，就是那样
and Core.h, I had the assertions as I mentioned earlier, and that's it
所以没有修改太多，最大的改动显然是glfw，就是那样，所以那就是我们的Window类
so I didn't modify much the big thing was obviously glfw, so that is it, okay, so that's our Window class
我希望你们喜欢这个视频，如果喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
I hope you guys enjoyed this video, if you did, you can hit that like button
你们也可以通过访问patreon.com/thecherno来帮助支持本系列
you can also help support this series by going to patreon.com/thecherno
一如既往地非常感谢所有支持本系列节目的赞助人
huge thank you as always to all the patreons that make this series possible
下次我们会在Window类中实现事件，我对此很兴奋，因为那很酷
next time, we're going to be implementing events into our Window class, I'm really excited about that, because that'll be cool
我们实际上可以移动鼠标，看看鼠标的位置
we'll actually be able to move the mouse, and see what the mouse position is
然后从那里开始，我们可能会接触一些图形的渲染
and then from there, we can probably get on to rendering graphics of some kind
并且可能在那之前，虽然建立了一个层系统
and probably before that, though setting up like a layer system
我们还可以讲到引擎架构之类的东西
and we can get on to more kind of engine architecture kind of stuff as well
但现在我们有了一个图形环境，可以在上面绘制图形，所以我们可能会很快添加ImGui
but now we have a graphics context,  where we can draw things onto, so we'll probably add ImGui to that pretty quickly
这样我们就可以真正开始看到，就像你们知道的，事物的视觉表现
so that we can actually start seeing, like you know, a visual representation of of things
并且这样我们就能获得更多的数据，那可能有点尴尬，或者记录起来很烦人
and actually just have more data available to us, that might be a bit awkward, or just annoying to log
所以那就是我们的计划，希望大家对此感到兴奋，我们下次见，拜
so yeah that's the plan, hope you guys are excited for that, I'll see you next time, goodbye